IN JANUARY 1991, IN SOUTHERN SOMALIA,
AFTER THE FALL OF THE RADICAL
GOVERNMENT OF MOHAMED SIAD BARRE,
A COALITION OF REBEL FACTIONS
LED BY THE COMMANDERS
OF THE UNITED SOMALIA CONGRESS,
MOHAMED FARRAH AIDID
AND ALI MAHDI MOHAMED,
CLASHED TO SEIZE POWER IN MOGADISHU.
THIS PROLONGED UNREST HAS CLAIMED
THE LIVES OF MANY INNOCENT CIVILIANS
AND LED TO A DRASTIC DECLINE
IN THE ECONOMY
TRIGGERING THE LARGEST HUMANITARIAN
CRISIS IN HISTORY
THE UNITED NATIONS,
IN ITS MISSION TO ADDRESS THIS CRISIS,
ESTABLISHED THE UNITED NATIONS
OPERATION IN SOMALIA (UNOSOM)
THROUGH THE UNITED NATIONS SECURITY
COUNCIL RESOLUTION 751 IN APRIL 1992.
ON MARCH 19TH, 1993,
THE MALAYSIAN CABINET AGREED
IN PRINCIPLE
FOR THE MALAYSIAN ARMED FORCES
TO DEPLOY AN INFANTRY COMBAT BATTALION
TO SERVE UNDER UNOSOM II (PHASE TWO).
THIS FORCE WAS NAMED
THE MALAYSIAN BATTALION, OR MALBATT.
DURING UNOSOM II,
MALBATT WAS ASSIGNED
AS THE QUICK REACTION FORCE (QRF),
AN ARMED MILITARY UNIT
CAPABLE OF RESPONDING
TO EMERGENCIES DURING THE OPERATION.
THIS IS THEIR STORY OF BRAVERY.
JULY 1993
You don't know, right?
- About his story.
- What?
Hey, take good care of yourself.
Okay, goodbye, everyone.
Peace be upon you.
Take good care of your mom. Bye.
Come here.
Be careful, Mail. Okay?
Promise you'll wait for me.
I promise to wait.
LT. DAHARI, COMMANDER OF PLATOON 4,
COMBAT TEAM ALPHA, CALL SIGN 21
15:30C, PARADISO HOTEL,
50 KM FROM MOGADISHU
Move!
Bring him out!
LCPL. SHAH, MEDIC,
COMBAT TEAM ALPHA, CALL SIGN 21C
I don't want to die!
Be a man!
You're okay.
Contact 2, CASEVAC now!
Zulu 21, this is Zulu 21, Charlie.
Request CASEVAC now.
Corporal Shah is injured, over.
Zulu 21, copy.
Report to call sign 2,
Corporal Shah is injured.
Yes, sir.
Zulu 21 Charlie,
what is the estimated time? Over.
Zulu 21 Charlie, 2 minutes, out.
Bring him out!
Don't move your hands.
You're okay.
Corporal Shah is injured!
Corporal Shah is injured.
Sir, Corporal Shah is injured.
MAJ. ADNAN, COMPANY COMMANDER
Escort him to APC safely.
Yes, sir!
Hello, Sierra 1. This is 29.
SITREP, over.
SGT. MUKHRIZ, SNIPER,
COMBAT TEAM ALPHA, CALL SIGN SIERRA 1
Hello, 29.
This is Sierra 1.
Target neutralized, out.
LCPL. NIK ZAINAL, REAR SHOOTER,
COMBAT TEAM ALPHA, CALL SIGN 21A
Shoot them.
Zul, get inside!
Standby inside!
There's a whole crowd out there!
I can help!
It's not your job!
LCPL. RAMLEE, APC COMMANDER,
COMBAT TEAM ALPHA, CALL SIGN 21A
If anything were to happen to you,
I don't want to have
to bring this rhinoceros back.
Hey!
Ali, get up!
Get up, Ali!
Get up!
Shoot them. Kill them.
Hello, 29.
This is Sierra 1.
Convoy Mike is coming from the north.
Strength three times Kilo,
Sierra Bravo, out.
Target seen.
Hurry up, Dahari.
Ali!
Don't worry.
Sir, are you okay?
Our people are coming. Leave now!
Or we will kill all these bastards!
Abdalle.
Let go of the hostages.
Are you deaf?
Our men will kill you! Get lost!
You'll die if you don't let them go.
We won't surrender.
Put your guns down or we'll kill him.
But why are you doing this?
They didn't hurt you.
That doesn't matter.
This is what our leader wants.
Where is he now?
Where is Hassan?
He left all of you to die.
Hello, 29. This is Sierra 1.
Convoy Mike close to HELANG.
RFI, out.
29, Sierra 1.
Neutralize target, out.
Let's go fight.
Take cover, go back.
Hello, 29. This is Sierra 1.
Neutralize target, out.
Hassan is not gone.
Don't listen to them.
Brother, you don't have to do this.
Let me help you.
You can't protect us, no one can.
Check on everyone who's injured.
- Call PRONTO.
- Yes, sir!
29, there are two hostages missing?
The others? Over.
Zulu 21.
I will send the others
to the RV now sir, over.
29, we need to rescue everyone.
Find the two hostages, quickly, out.
Sir, this is a big hotel.
How are we going to look for them?
We have trapped them from downstairs.
Where are they going to go?
Okay, listen here.
Hamid, Jumaat, and Khalid follow me.
The others
take the hostages to the RV now.
- Yes, sir!
Bring them back, quickly!
Bring them back and move fast!
Quickly, go!
Hello, all call sign.
Move to the pickup point, now, out.
Okay.
Hurry up!
Hello, Sierra 1. This is 29.
Move to the RV now, over.
Sierra 1, copy, out.
29, out.
Sierra 2, pack up and return to RV.
Bastard.
Hassan, all your men are dead.
The ones coming will not be here
in time to save you.
It's over.
It's not over until I say so.
Leave or I will kill these two white pigs.
They will kill you before that can happen.
Please, surrender
- and we will protect you.
- They will torture me
to find out the Supreme Leader's hideout.
Do you think I am stupid?
Please, we are good people.
We are brothers.
- You can trust us.
- You are a friend of our enemy
and I will never trust a traitor.
Hassan, I am not.
I want to save my people.
I want to save you.
Get lost.
The package is safe.
Understand?
Hamid, Mukhriz, quickly.
Hello, all call sign.
Good job, everyone.
Return to base now, out.
MALBATT BASE
LCPL. WAHID, REAR SHOOTER,
COMBAT TEAM CHARLIE, CALL SIGN 21C
Here.
Get ready.
Is everything okay?
All right, nice ball.
- Goal!
- One more time.
Ninety-five.
Ninety-six.
Ninety-seven.
I only asked for 100
and you're already like this.
-You can't even do 100?
- 99,
-I cannot do anymore.
- 100.
Push! You can.
I can't!
- You can.
- I can't anymore.
What's wrong with you?
Don't talk about faith.
Giving me your feet is not funny.
I didn't give you my feet.
I gave you my socks.
You said you wanted
to make the country proud.
You can't even make us proud.
Do you want to make the country proud?
Wash your socks first.
It smells like
a lizard's carcass, you know?
Can you move aside?
You think because you're big,
I'm scared of you?
I didn't do anything.
What's wrong with you?
CPL. ASLAM, APC COMMANDER
Your chest is jiggling.
- Abdalle.
- Zul, come play with us.
Ramlee.
- "Tight face," say it.
- "Tight face."
- Tight.
- You play too much, bro.
- Peace be upon you.
Oh, Fatimah
We have received a call from UNOSOM.
They thanked MALBATT's assault team
for successfully rescuing
all the hostages.
The CNN also expressed
their utmost gratitude
for rescuing them.
But you have one complaint.
There is a complaint
that our attack method
on the Grand Suite is too extreme.
- They could've been killed...
- But sir.
In an urgent situation like that,
that was the only way we had, sir.
Before more Somalis come to attack us...
I know you've done your best.
A few minutes of delay
might have caused more casualties.
Nobody is blaming you.
You are only following orders
and orders are orders.
Let us settle this one.
You may go now.
Thank you, sir.
It's actually good
that someone complained.
Why is that?
Only then will they know
Malaysia can also perform rescue missions,
not just America.
PVT. ISA, APC DRIVER,
COMBAT TEAM CHARLIE, CALL SIGN 12C
Sounds like fun over there, darling.
Who else came to the house?
Mak Jah is coming in a bit.
She's sending over porridge.
Don't worry.
Many people can take care of me here.
Do you still keep the photo
in your shirt pocket?
Like you always tell me.
Until forever, dear.
Until forever.
Okay, darling.
Peace be upon you.
Peace be upon you too.
Is anybody there?
I feel like I'm playing alone.
Look, I'll teach you how to fold.
Go high.
Hurry, skipper.
Okay, high ball.
Go high like the KOMTAR Building.
What's wrong with you guys?
Can't you see people are walking here?
- Does it hurt?
- Pity the kid.
If you don't know how to play, don't play.
Brother, come.
What's with the gloomy face?
We're only joking.
Whose photo is that?
Your wife?
Corporal.
Mind your own business.
Why are you so arrogant?
Enough.
Let's go.
Come and join us.
Sitting by yourself,
you'll make yourself gloomier
and become dumber. Come.
It's okay, Corporal. I'm fine.
- Thank you.
- It's not okay.
Come over.
We'll teach you to become stronger.
You have to be a bit braver, right?
- Like…
- Like you?
Sir.
Have you been to war?
- Never, sir.
If you've only gone for recces in town,
there is no need to show off.
It's really quite embarrassing.
Then you have the nerve to bully
like regular crooks.
Are you soldiers or school kids?
- Soldiers, sir!
Are you okay, Isa?
I'm okay, sir.
Thank you, sir!
At ease.
This kid, I swear.
Was that bullying?
- Bullying?
- No.
- No, right?
- This is bullying.
- Hey!
- Kids nowadays!
- You…
So sensitive!
Lee. Zul.
Hurry up and play.
What are you waiting for?
Talking about girls…
Don't tell me you need me
to teach you that.
Hey, where are you guys going?
Hey! You left us for women.
- Peace be upon you, sir.
- Peace be upon you too.
Sir.
Osman.
I have just received a call
from Colonel Ward,
Operations Colonel from the US Army
at the UNOSOM HQ.
Sounds important, sir.
In wartime,
even unimportant things can be important.
Sir.
But don't worry.
I think this mission
is just a regular one.
So according to Colonel Ward,
Somali terrorists will attack New Port
at 17:00 today.
So they are asking for assistance
to strengthen the security force
at New Port.
So I suggest
you bring Bravo Company with you.
If I'm not mistaken,
Alpha Company has a mission tomorrow.
Yes, sir. I will inform Adnan
to prepare his men.
Any questions?
This is just a regular mission right, sir?
Yes, I am sure of it.
There will be no terrorist attack
this afternoon.
Anyway, those Somali terrorists
won't be so crazy to attack now
when they see our security forces.
Yes, sir.
Thank you, sir.
I'm the same.
I don't know either.
While I was on the recce just now,
I saw some Somalis
who weren't all that happy with us.
Who cares about them?
We're doing our jobs, right?
No, I mean.
What are we doing here?
It's like we're supporting America,
but they don't even know Malaysia.
I had to explain, you know?
Thailand. Singapore.
We're here in the middle, Malaysia.
It's to that extent.
Meanwhile, the Somalis look at us
as if we're traitors of our faith.
What's our story, actually?
Traitors of our faith?
Doing good doesn't take into account
of what your religion is, Mail.
Let me ask you,
does Islam teach us to let people starve?
No.
Has Islam taught us
to capture innocent people?
- No.
- No, Mail.
So when we get orders,
we just do our jobs.
Let the Commander worry about the rest.
Goodness.
Busy fighting wars outside,
busy discussing inside.
LT. JOHAN, COMMANDER OF PLATOON 3
Dahari, you were so lucky yesterday.
You got to go on the rescue mission.
Where's the luck?
That's lucky. Why is that not lucky?
From the time I arrived until now,
it's always recce.
It's boring.
What am I going to tell
the people of Alor Gajah?
I can't say I went on walks here.
I'm not a tour guide.
I want to tell
some war stories too, right?
Go and request it then.
I'm not asking for a full-on war.
A little action is all.
Sir.
Bravo Company order for standby now, sir.
For a new mission, sir.
- Now?
- Yes, sir.
All right, thank you.
It's always Bravo. It's never-ending.
What about Alpha?
They are really playing favorites.
Hey, don't leave.
If you leave, I'll be very sad, you know?
Who am I going to flirt with here?
Goodness, your eyes are so beautiful.
Yes, I know. It's blue.
I seek forgiveness from God.
Take this.
Attention Bravo Company.
Special Operation Warrant.
No movements before 16:00C.
Be ready for combat, RV in the New Port.
Command will be delivered in the RV.
Action.
- Move!
0 Bravo.
We've lived in this war for some time now.
In war,
nobody wins,
everybody loses.
Over.
29, question.
Why so serious?
I thought
it was just a regular mission, over.
Just felt like talking.
We see the same things every day.
Operations Officer.
0 Bravo wait, out.
Has Bravo Company reached New Port?
Not yet, sir.
We've just received new orders.
9, keep heading towards New Port
and wait there.
Call sign 1 will move in a while,
together with the US and Pakistan, over.
29, roger that.
Question.
What is our latest mission? Over.
9, I'm not sure myself.
So don't go anywhere.
0 Bravo will join you there.
Wait until we receive
the next bit of intel.
Over.
- Move!
- Move now!
Faster.
Corporal, why so many rounds of bullets?
Major's orders.
Now this is what you call a war.
UNOSOM BASE
Do you guys want to hear?
My new joke.
Mus.
I haven't received any information.
According to Colonel Rahman,
the US military and the Pakistani military
will come here
for a briefing on the mission.
We will probably enter
the territory of Farrah Aidid's followers.
But sir, we've never been there.
That's dangerous territory, sir.
I need to remind you
that the place has no protection.
We can be attacked
by the enemy at any time.
Remember our training.
The most important thing
is to take care of your team members.
In this job,
you're always confronted by death.
But if we do it together,
if God wills, He will be with us.
Sir, from 9.
91, this is 9, over.
91 copy, over.
9, they have arrived, out.
They are here.
91, we're not taxis. You can't do this.
The US Army is not proficient
at using APC.
Our APC will be damaged, over.
9, Major Osman, calm down.
MALBATT talked it over with UNOSOM HQ.
MALBATT will bring the commander,
rear gunner,
and a driver for every APC, over.
91, question.
Our assault troop, over.
9, we have done our best.
Orders are orders.
We have to carry on with this mission.
Out.
Lee, why just the assault team?
Because of orders.
Sir, this is unfair.
We have a right
- to follow this mission, sir.
- Hamid.
Sir, please talk to them.
If they want to use our APC,
they have to take us along.
Or we won't follow, sir.
Calm down, this is an order.
You yourself said we are better
than these white soldiers.
- We can help!
- Hamid.
Rude.
Hamid!
Calm down.
Sir, we want to follow this mission.
We really want to follow this mission.
What are we lacking, sir?
This is why the Somalis call us traitors.
Because we just do
what the white soldiers tell us like cows.
Hamid, do you realize
who you're talking to?
Respect, Hamid.
Respect.
This mission is not for you
to show who is greater.
Who do you think you are?
Every little thing must involve you.
God?
Colonel Rahman has tried.
Understand this?
Orders are orders.
You can all return to base.
I will return to base with them
to further observe this mission.
All decisions are not mine anymore.
Everything is up to you.
Dismissed.
Rank.
Attention.
Get in.
I'll be all right.
My first time out of the village
and I'm at a place like this.
I haven't even been to Kuala Lumpur.
Isa, it won't be long.
In two or three hours, we can go back.
COMBAT TEAM ALPHA, CALL SIGN 21A,
ON THE WAY TO OBJECTIVE A
Why are they stopping?
- Hello, 29. This is 21.
- Sir.
Pakistan's tank has stopped, over.
29 wait, out.
Sir, Pakistan is withdrawing because
they don't have night vision goggles.
They don't dare to proceed.
19, that's ridiculous.
It's not like Pakistan
has never fought at night, over.
29, do we proceed, Mad?
Pakistan is not going to help, over.
19, we have no choice.
Orders are orders, over.
29, I know, Mad.
But even a big country like that
is leaving, over.
Nan, you saw just now during the briefing.
How the white soldiers looked at us.
They're ridiculous.
They don't even know where Malaysia is.
Nan.
Why are we here?
Sir.
Colonel Lawrence wants us
to carry on with the mission.
Tell him we'll go in right now.
Hello, 21. This is 29,
overtake the Pakistan tank.
Advance forward
then go right towards Objective A.
Move now, out.
What's this?
If you want to leave, just leave.
What are you doing here?
Shoot them.
Damn it, go back to your country.
I can't see anything.
Shoot them, shoot the APC.
Pok Nik! Are you okay?
- Okay. Are you okay?
- Okay.
Shoot them.
Lee, I can't see anything.
What are you talking about?
You still can't see
with such a wide windscreen.
How can I see? It's dark.
My windscreen is full of bullets.
Totally blind.
Pok Nik, take care of this for a while.
They knew we were coming.
They were ready for us.
Lee, I have a bad feeling.
Good.
That bad feeling is part of our job.
Okay. What now?
What are they doing?
Why aren't we moving yet?
Hello, 21. This is 21 Alpha.
We have passed the Pakistani tank,
but we are receiving contact
of heavy attacks.
What are your next orders? Over.
21, we are trapped behind the tank.
Head straight and then turn right.
Head straight and then turn right, over.
21 Alpha, left or right? Over.
21, go right.
Don't go left, go right.
Right now, out.
Zul, just take the next right ahead. Now.
Aim the tire.
Lee, our tire is damaged.
What should we do?
You want to go out and change the tire?
Just go!
Just go straight
and turn right at the front there.
- Hey!
- Lee, I can't go right.
There's a barricade.
The order is to turn right,
so just turn right.
I can't go in. There's a barricade.
Do it until you can.
Do it until you can!
Do it until you can, Zul!
Pok Nik, why so quiet at the back?
Shoot at them!
Ask these white soldiers to help
instead of just staring into space!
Shoot them.
- Give it to me. Quick.
- Okay.
Zul!
Goodness, this is bad.
Zul, move forward a little bit more.
- There's a junction to the right, take it.
- Okay.
Lee, there's a barrier here too.
You go ahead and see
if there are other junctions up front.
Load the RPG and shoot them.
RPG ahead!
Zul, you just turned left.
You should turn right.
The attack was getting stronger, Lee.
I cannot go forward anymore.
I don't want to die here today.
Hello, 21. This is 21 Alpha.
We had to go left, over.
Hello, 29. This is 21, over.
29 send, over.
21, call sign 21 Alpha and 54 Alpha
have passed the tank,
but cannot be contacted.
- Cannot be contacted, over.
- Sir.
29 wait, out.
Sir, we have to move now.
- Colonel Lawrence is having a fit.
- He hasn't seen my fit yet! Wait a minute!
Tell him to tell Pakistan
to move all their tanks now.
Yes, sir.
Hello, 21 Alpha. This is 21.
Where are you, Ramlee? Over.
Damn it!
Hello, 21. This is 21 Alpha.
We had to turn left, over.
21?
Nothing heard.
Out.
We're lost.
Hello, 23. This is 29, over.
23 send, over.
29, call sign 21 is ahead.
They receive heavy attacks.
Change the order of march.
You're leading the Alpha convoy now.
Move forward with your platoon
and we will follow from behind.
Be careful there are terrorists everywhere
all the way to National Street, out.
Sure, it's a place I'm used to.
Sir, how do we go right, sir?
Hello, all call sign 23.
Move towards the junction
and shoot the barricade in front.
Shoot the barricade in front, out.
Hello, 29. This is 23.
I need to dismount, over.
29 it's dangerous for you, over.
23, I need to dismount
for the mission, out.
Wan, give covering fire.
I'm going out.
Sir, it's dangerous outside.
No, right?
Stupid.
Hurry!
Hey!
What?
Zul, you stop right ahead.
Our heroes are getting out.
Pok Nik, to your left. Eleven o'clock.
Lee, what are you doing?
- Quick, shoot them.
- Shoot them.
Lee, one o'clock, RPG!
Zul!
What are you doing?
RPG!
Zul!
Are you okay?
How many times do I have to tell you?
They were aiming at you just now.
01:09C
COMBAT TEAM CHARLIE, CALL SIGN 12C,
ON THE WAY TO OBJECTIVE B
Hello, 12. This is 12 Charlie.
Where are we heading now? Over.
12, later at the National Street,
turn left and then head straight
for Objective B, over.
12 Charlie copy, out.
- Kill them.
- Shoot them.
Damn it.
Why did we stop?
Corporal, are we really going to…
Hello, 12 Charlie. This is 12.
Did I tell you to stop? Over.
12 Charlie, we have a situation, over.
Hello, 12 Charlie. This is 12.
Scare the boy so that he runs away, hurry.
We are already late, out.
What did they do to this country?
That boy grew up as bold as this.
Sir.
FORWARD OPERATING BASE
I'm sorry for being late, sir.
Too many attacks from New Port to here.
The Somalis
are really eager for war tonight.
Intelligence Officer.
CPT. MANSOR, INTELLIGENCE OFFICER
Yes, sir.
All right, I was wrong.
Before this, I had assumed
that this was an ordinary operation.
But from my conversation
with UNOSOM just now,
we found out that the US soldiers
have tried to extract their men
four times already
to no avail.
Now,
only us.
Only Malaysia volunteered
for this rescue mission.
Is that why we entered the town
using only one entryway?
Because the other routes are unusable?
This operation,
it's a suicide operation, sir.
Operation Officer.
What are you talking about?
Don't you have faith
in your men's abilities?
I trust them with my life, sir.
01:13C, CALL SIGN 12C
Corporal, take a left in another 100 m.
Clear, no barrier.
Okay, Isa. Be careful.
Sir, new information.
There's a group of US soldiers
trapped at crash site 2
waiting for us.
- Do we know their location?
- No, sir.
But Little Bird will show the way.
Copy, I will instruct the others.
12 copy, over.
19, out.
Hello, all call sign 12.
Follow the chopper above
and go forward now.
Out.
Isa, NVG.
Quickly load all the weapons.
Don't let them rescue our enemies.
Sir.
Hello, 12. This is 12 Bravo.
A Humvee in the back got destroyed
by a landmine, over.
Hello, 19. This is 12.
19, I haven't heard anything
from the US side.
Accomplish the mission, out.
We'll carry on with the mission.
What is it now?
RPG.
Shoot them.
Isa, are you okay?
Why haven't we moved?
Hello, 12. This is 19.
Find the source of the attacks
and destroy them.
If they shoot down Little Bird,
we are finished.
Out.
Where is it?
How many times do I have to say?
Just stay in the APC.
I already told you!
Hello, all call sign 12.
I need covering fire, I will dismount.
Out.
From the corner.
Damn! Go!
Rear gunner, front building.
Follow my tracer.
Yes, sir.
Hello, all call sign 12,
follow my tracer's direction.
Follow the tracer, out.
Take that!
Hello, 19. This is 12.
Target destroyed, over.
19, good job.
Continue the mission, out.
01:13C, CALL SIGN 21A, 54A
Save those bullets.
Zul, are you okay?
All heroes get hurt, right?
Ramlee!
Ramlee.
Hill.
Big.
Ramlee.
Our vehicle has been destroyed to pieces.
What about you?
We can't even start the engine.
It's a piece of junk now.
It's okay.
All these white soldiers can help us.
Zul, are you okay?
Ramlee, the US has medic.
We dismount now.
Bailout procedure.
Let me hold you.
Zul, patience.
Hold on for a while, Zul.
Pok Nik, bring Zul and follow us.
I want to recce up ahead.
Abdalle.
Ramlee?
Peace be upon you.
- Hang on, a bit more.
- Slowly.
Here, sit here.
Go inside.
Hello, 29.
This is 23.
The road ahead is getting narrow,
let us recce first.
- Over.
- 29, copy that, out.
Hello, all call sign 23.
Siege the objective ahead.
Make sure they can't touch us.
Understand? Out.
Move the APC.
What? Damn it!
We are being targeted
with something, retreat.
What's this?
Hello, all call sign 23.
Where are you going?
Our mission is not finished yet, over.
23 Bravo.
The US soldiers want to leave now, over.
23, we are instructed
to bring back the US soldiers.
Dead or alive.
Now go back to your position
and sit quietly.
Understand? Out.
04:00C
Lee, no one knows where we are.
Who's going to save us?
I'm also blank right now.
Don't you work for the government?
This is what you get?
Lee, we have to go.
Let's go. Hold on for a little bit.
LOST TEAM
OBJECTIVE A
OBJECTIVE B
COMBAT TEAM CHARLIE, CALL SIGN 12
Hello, all call sign 1.
We have arrived at the dispersal point
for Objective B.
Inform the US soldiers to dismount.
Out.
Isa, standby.
We'll arrive soon. Understand?
Understood, Corporal.
Darling.
RPG!
Rear gunner, are you all okay at the back?
I'm fine, sir.
Sir, we got hit by a land mine.
The car is destroyed, sir.
At least you're okay.
God is the greatest.
Go inside.
Come to prayer.
God is the greatest.
Isa. Recite the Shahada, Isa.
Come to prayer.
God is the greatest.
Isa. Recite the Shahada, Isa.
Isa, wake up!
Isa!
God.
I seek forgiveness from God. Isa.
Isa.
God is the greatest.
Hello, 19. This is 12.
Private Isa KIA.
Out.
We have to contact UNOSOM
and ask the Americans
to bring the Black Hawk
for CASEVAC now, sir.
I've spoken to them,
but the area is too dangerous.
A lot of choppers were shot down.
Why are the American lives more valuable
than the lives of our men, sir?
Our men know their duty.
Orders are orders!
Have you forgotten your duty,
Operations Officer?
Have faith in orders.
Have faith in our team.
Have faith that we will solve this mission
without further loss of lives.
That's what we should be doing!
To God we belong
and to God we shall return
Hello, 13. This is 19.
Call sign 12 is under attack.
Go forward and help them, over.
13 copy.
We will make a move now, over.
19, out.
If it's delayed like this, we're screwed.
Sir.
Sir, are you okay?
Wan, cover at the front.
I want to see in case there's an ambush.
Yes, sir.
Sir, are you okay?
Are you okay, sir?
Are you okay?
Praise be to God, sir.
It's lucky that you moved, sir, or else…
Understood?
Ali, pull the chopper out now.
Yes, sir.
Put more pressure. A little bit more.
Praise be to God.
29.
Move to the RV now.
Move to the RV now, out.
Hello, 29. This is 21.
Call sign 21 Alpha and 54 Alpha
are still lost.
What do we do? Over.
29.
Don't worry.
I will contact the Americans.
We won't go home
until we find all our men, out.
Pok Nik!
Pok Nik, cover me!
Abdalle!
Lee, we have no way out.
We've been surrounded.
Son of a bitch.
Dear, God.
Unite us with our brothers in arms.
There is no power and no strength
except with God's permission.
God is the greatest!
Sir, all the Rangers at Objective B
have been rescued,
but Super 64 is a total loss.
Two pilots cannot be detected.
Combat Team Charlie
is given the order to retreat.
Hello, 19. This is 12.
I see a red flare up ahead.
It looks like our signal.
It's 1 km from here, over.
19.
It's call sign 21, right? Over.
12, I'm not sure sir, out.
Sir, we can confirm that it's our condor.
Copy that.
Ask them to accompany our platoon
for a rescue mission.
Sir, they informed us earlier
that they couldn't make it.
Hello, 13. This is 19.
Move forward
to assist the strayed APC, over.
13, I'm in the lead
and I'm not strayed, over.
19, calm down. It's not you.
Two APCs from Combat Team Alpha, over.
13, copy.
I misunderstood, over.
19, the chopper above
will show you the way to our APC.
Go quickly.
Flare reveals their position to the enemy.
They are vulnerable now, out.
You wanted a war so bad, right?
Let's go.
Now let's go to war.
Hello, all call sign 13.
Move forward and follow me.
Move forward and follow me, out.
Come out and shoot there.
Lee.
Lee!
The first light is in an hour.
We won't make it out
during the daytime, Lee.
Hurry, find a spot to engage.
Fire at them.
Get into position, stand by.
They're approaching. Open fire on them.
You think I'm scared?
Faris, hit it.
05:57C
Faris, turn right.
What are you waiting for? Hurry.
Abdalle.
- Get up!
- I can't leave.
Abdalle.
You can still do that, dumbass!
Lee, we've got to move.
Come.
Pok Nik, stop.
Faster.
Ramlee.
Sir, Combat Team Alpha and Charlie
are on their way back to base, sir.
Our mission is successful, sir.
Operation Officer.
- Well done, sir.
- Good job.
Intelligence Officer, any more casualties?
Praise be to God. None, sir.
Only a few were injured,
but are still stable.
Intelligence Officer, instruct the US
to destroy two APCs of ours.
I don't want our assets
to fall into the enemy's hands.
Yes, sir.
I can share stories
about wars like this with no shame
with the people of Alor Gajah.
I won't be surprised
if they build a mosque in my name.
How did it hit?
I have no idea.
We have to ask the boss.
Are you harmed? Okay?
I'm okay. Praise be to God.
- Johan, Dahari, and Ilyas.
- Hey.
You're still here.
Yes, praise be to God.
We are the 19th Battalion
of the Royal Malay Regiment.
Whatever the issue is,
we face it together.
Have you forgotten?
If you carve this,
orange blood will come out.
This is the face of a war soldier.
Why are your faces clean?
Answer it.
Mus.
Mus, are you okay?
It all happened too fast.
I couldn't do anything.
What happened?
- Sir.
I will make sure
his wife and children know
that he died a hero.
Lee.
He can still flirt in this condition?
If he can breathe, he can flirt.
Did I succeed
in making the country proud?
Make the country proud? I'm not sure.
But you made me proud.
Zul.
Take care of yourself.
Eat your meds. Make sure you eat right.
You need to...
Speaking the white man's language.
So…
What now?
The world knows us now.
What else?
THAT IS WHY WE ORDAINED
FOR THE CHILDREN OF ISRAEL
THAT WHOEVER TAKES A LIFE
UNLESS AS A PUNISHMENT FOR MURDER
OR MISCHIEF IN THE LAND,
IT WILL BE AS IF
THEY KILLED ALL OF HUMANITY.
WHOEVER SAVES A LIFE, IT WILL BE
AS IF THEY SAVED ALL OF HUMANITY.
ALTHOUGH OUR MESSENGERS ALREADY
CAME TO THEM WITH CLEAR PROOF,
MANY OF THEM STILL TRANSGRESSED
AFTERWARD THROUGH THE LAND.
SURAH AL-MAIDAH: 32
THE NAMES OF THE CHARACTERS
IN THIS FILM ARE FICTITIOUS,
INSPIRED BY THE REAL PEOPLE
OF THE STORY.
THE MALBATT TEAM HAS RESCUED
MORE THAN 70 US RANGERS
WHO WERE TRAPPED IN AN ATTACK
AT THE BAKARA MARKET, MOGADISHU.
THE COURAGEOUS ACT
BY THE MEMBERS OF MALBATT
RECEIVED UNOFFICIAL RECOGNITION FROM
THE US ARMY OFFICERS AND UNOSOM II.
LOCAL NEWS REPORT IN 1993
THE MALAYSIAN ARMY WAS ONLY AWARDED
OFFICIAL RECOGNITION
FROM THE US DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE
IN THE PENTAGON
20 YEARS AFTER THE TRAGIC INCIDENT
IN MOGADISHU.
THAT RECOGNITION WAS GIVEN
BY THE ACTING UNITED STATES ASSISTANT
SECRETARY OF STATE
FOR POLITICAL-MILITARY AFFAIRS,
TOM KELLY, IN 2013.
AZNAN'S FAMILY DEVASTATED
AFTER RECEIVING THE NEWS
MALAYSIAN HERO KILLED IN SOMALIA
CORPORAL MAT AZNAN AWANG,
APC DRIVER PLATOON 2, ALPHA COMPANY
28 DECEMBER 1961 - 4 OCTOBER 1993
ON OCTOBER 9TH, 1993,
THE BODY OF CORPORAL MAT AZNAN
WAS FLOWN BACK HOME FROM MOGADISHU
AND BURIED AT AN ISLAMIC CEMETERY
IN PARIT PANJANG, BALING, KEDAH.
MAJOR AB AZIZ BIN AB LATIF
COMBAT TEAM CHARLIE COMMANDER
4 AUGUST 1955 - 12 OCTOBER 2022
IF IT WASN'T FOR MAJOR AZIZ
SHARING STORIES ABOUT THIS MISSION,
I WOULDN'T HAVE BEEN INSPIRED
TO CREATE THIS FILM.
OUR BRAVE HEROES
WILL NEVER BE FORGOTTEN.
ALL CHARACTERS IN THIS WORK
ARE FICTITIOUS
ANY RESEMBLANCE TO REAL PERSON,
DEAD OR ALIVE, IS PURELY COINCIDENTAL